Finding Aid for the Kenneth Rexroth Papers LSC.0175
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 6: Printed materials, 1936-1976; 36 boxes (18 linear ft.).
  - Subseries 6E: Newspapers,., 1938-1975; 5 boxes.
    - UWM Post (The)., 1971.; 1 item. (Box 141, Folder 10)
      University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee student paper
    - VDRSVP., 1969.; 1 item. (Box 141, Folder 11)
      Alternative paper
    - Wonderland., 1973 July.; 1 item. (Box 141, Folder 12)
      Sunday magazine
    - Worker's Age., 1940-1941.; ca. 20 items. (Box 141, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 6F: Periodicals and newsletters,., 1944-1975; 6.5 boxes.
    Arranged alphabetically by the title of the publication. See box 120 for the oversize publication Shelter (1973), and two unidentified Japanese periodicals, one featuring an interview with Rexroth.
    - American Negro Woman Newsletter., 1960 March.; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 1)
    - American PEN Newsletter., 1974 May-June.; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 2)
      Published by the American Center of P.E.N. International
    - AMPO., 1974.; 2 items. (Box 142, Folder 3)
      Japan-Asia quarterly review
    - Art News., 1968 September.; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 4)
    - Black Theatre., 1968.; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 5)
    - California Librarian., 1964 April.; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 6)
    - California Monthly., 1961 June.; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 7)
    - California Today., 1969.; 2 items. (Box 142, Folder 8)
      Legislative report
    - Catholic C.O. (The)., 1947.; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 9)
    - Centro Intercultual de Documentacion., ca. 1971.; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 10)
      Mexican newsletter, featuring an article by Ivan Illich
    - Chanoyu., 1975.; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 11)
      Tea and the arts of Japan
    - Chinatown News., 1958 March.; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 12)
    - Church of the Ascension Parish Magazine., 1944 September.; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 13)
    - Clear Creek., 1972.; 2 items. (Box 142, Folder 14)
    - Commentary., 1958 November.; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 15)
    - Commonweal., 1966-1971.; 10 items. (Box 142, Folder 16)
    - Congressional Record., 1965 January.; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 17)
    - Continuum., 1970.; 1 item. (Box 142, Folder 18)
    - Cry California., 1965-1966.; 2 items. (Box 142, Folder 19)
    - Dialogue., 1970-1971.; 3 items. (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - Dispatch., 1969.; 3 items. (Box 143, Folder 2)
      Vietnam newsletter; letter from the editor and prospectus
    - Earth., 1971 August.; 1 item. (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - Earth Read-Out., 1969-1973.; ca. 25 items. (Box 143, Folder 4)
    - Ecology Action Newsletter., 1969.; 1 item. (Box 143, Folder 5)
      Published by the Ecology Action Educational Institute
    - EMHA Newsletter., 1973, 1975.; 2 items. (Box 143, Folder 6)
      Published by the Ecumenical Ministry in the Haight Ashbury
    - Evergreen (1-2 of 3)., 1968-1970.; 10 items. (Box 143, Folder 7-8)
    - Evergreen (3 of 3)., 1971.; 8 items. (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Farm Labor., 1964.; 1 item. (Box 144, Folder 2)
      Published by Citizens for Farm Labor, on equal rights for agricultural workers
    - Flightime., 1969 May.; 1 item. (Box 144, Folder 3)
      Continental Airlines magazine
    - Focus on Asian Studies., 1973. (Box 144, Folder 4)
    - Galley Sail (The)., 1957.; 1 item. (Box 144, Folder 5)
      News of the Clan MacNeil Alliance of California
    - HAIL., 1967.; 2 items. (Box 144, Folder 6)
      Haight-Ashbury-Ink-Link
    - Hard Times., 1969-1970.; 3 items. (Box 144, Folder 7)
    - Harper's Magazine., 1965 June.; 1 item. (Box 144, Folder 8)
      New American poets by Rexroth
    - Holy Cross Magazine (The)., 1948 October.; 1 item. (Box 144, Folder 9)
    - Innkeeper (The)., 1960 June.; 1 item. (Box 144, Folder 10)
      Published by the Hotel and Restaurant Society of City College of San Francisco
    - International Poetry Institute, INC Newsletter., 1969.; 1 item. (Box 144, Folder 11)
    - It's Vital., 1953 July-August.; 1 item. (Box 144, Folder 12)
      Published by the San Francisco Tuberculosis Association (portrait of Marie Rexroth on cover)
    - Journal of Reading., 1979 February.; 1 item. (Box 144, Folder 13)
    - Land Economics., 1973 November.; 1 item. (Box 144, Folder 14)
    - Liberation., 1968-1971.; 14 items. (Box 144, Folder 15-17)
    - Little Chronicle (The)., 1968 May.; 1 item. (Box 144, Folder 18)
      Martin Luther King, Jr. memorial issue
    - Manas., 1967 December 13.; 1 item. (Box 145, Folder 1)
    - Material for Thought., 1972.; 1 item. (Box 145, Folder 2)
    - Montecito News Letter., 1971.; 1 item. (Box 145, Folder 3)
      Published by the Montecito protective and Improvement Association
    - Month (The)., 1971 April.; 1 item. (Box 145, Folder 4)
      Christian review
    - Mundus Artium., 1968.; 1 item. (Box 145, Folder 5)
    - Nation (The)., 1959-1972.; 16 items. (Box 145, Folder 6-7)
      Includes articles by Rexroth
    - National Poetry Foundation Newsletter., 1961 July.; 1 item. (Box 145, Folder 8)
    - New Generation., 1969.; 2 items. (Box 145, Folder 9)
    - New Journalist., 1975 March.; 1 item. (Box 145, Folder 10)
    - New Leader (The)., 1961-1967.; 4 items. (Box 145, Folder 11)
    - New Mexico Review and Legislative Journal (The)., 1970.; 1 item. (Box 145, Folder 12)
      Liberal newsletter
    - New Schools Exchange Newsletter., 1971.; 4 items. (Box 145, Folder 13)
    - News and Views., 1965 November.; 1 item. (Box 145, Folder 14)
      Published by the San Francisco Police-Community Relations Committee
    - News from [California Legislature] Willie L. Brown., 1969 May.; 2 items. (Box 145, Folder 15)
      Re: report of the Select Committee on Campus Disorders
    - Newsletter of the Regional Arts Council., 1966 March.; 1 item. (Box 145, Folder 16)
      Published by the RAS the San Francisco Bay Area
    - On the Move., 1969.; 1 item. (Box 145, Folder 17)
      Published by Immaculate Heart College Press
    - Orange County Sun., 1965-1966.; 2 items. (Box 145, Folder 18)
    - Oui., 1973 January.; 1 item. (Box 145, Folder 19)
    - Pacific (The)., 1965.; 1 item. (Box 146, Folder 1)
      Published by the United Church of Christ
    - Poet Lore., 1968-1969.; 2 items. (Box 146, Folder 2)
      World literature and drama
    - Poetry Now., 1968.; 1 item. (Box 146, Folder 3)
      University of Wisconsin Extension newsletter
    - Poetry Society of America Bulletin., 1958 February.; 1 item. (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - Postal Bell (The)., 1967.; 1 item. (Box 146, Folder 5)
      Published by the Japanese American Philatelic Society
    - Ramparts., 1969 May.; 1 item. (Box 146, Folder 6)
    - Reading Connection (The)., 1980.; 1 item. (Box 146, Folder 7)
    - Recorder., no date.; 1 item. (Box 146, Folder 8)
    - Research Reporter (The)., 1967.; 1 item. (Box 146, Folder 9)
      Published by the Center for Research and Development in Higher Education, UC Berkeley
    - Ronin., 1972-1973.; 6 items. (Box 146, Folder 10)
    - Royal Echoes., 1972 June.; 1 item. (Box 146, Folder 11)
      Published by Christ the King High School, Middle Village, New York
    - Sadakichi Hartmann Newsletter., 1970-1973.; 11 items. (Box 146, Folder 12)
      Published by the University of California, Riverside
    - San Francisco (1-3 of 7)., 1968-1969 December.; 11 items. (Box 146, Folder 13-15)
    - San Francisco (4-7 of 7)., 1970 February-1971 December.; 21 items. (Box 147, Folder 1-4)
    - San Francisco Book Review., 1971.; 2 items. (Box 147, Folder 5)
      Special issue featuring Robert Bly
    - San Francisco Human Rights Commission Notes., 1966 February.; 1 item. (Box 147, Folder 6)
    - San Francisco Territorial News., 1961 January.; 1 item. (Box 147, Folder 7)
    - Santa Barbara Survival Times., 1970 May.; 1 item. (Box 147, Folder 8)
    - Saturday Review., 1959, 1967.; 4 items. (Box 147, Folder 9)
    - Sierra Club Bulletin., 1937, 1966.; 2 items. (Box 148, Folder 1)
    - Sun (The)., 1975.; 1 item. (Box 148, Folder 2)
      Japanese-language arts publication featuring Ukiyoe prints made by Kitagawa- Utamaro
    - Synanon (The)., 1969.; 1 item. (Box 148, Folder 3)
    - TWA Ambassador., 1969.; 1 item. (Box 148, Folder 4)
    - Views and Comments., 1955.; 1 item. (Box 148, Folder 5)
      Published by the Libertarian League
    - Washington Watch., 1974 July.; 1 item. (Box 148, Folder 6)
      Private newsletter by Tristram Coffin
    - Western World Review., 1967-1969.; 3 items. (Box 148, Folder 7)
    - William James Newsletter., 1973.; 1 item. (Box 148, Folder 8)
    - Win., 1966 September.; 1 item. (Box 148, Folder 9)
    - Zero Population Growth California Newsletter., 1969.; 1 item. (Box 148, Folder 10)
- Series 7: Teaching, 1953-1974; 9 boxes (4.5 linear ft.).
  Arranged in Subseries A-C as follows:
  A. Lectures, 1953-1974 (2 boxes).
  B. San Francisco State College, 1957-1966 (1 box).
  C. UC Santa Barbara, 1968-1974 (6 boxes).
  - Subseries 7A: Lectures,., 1953-1974; 2 boxes.
    Correspondence and printed materials related to Rexroth's lecture dates and tours. The original contents of the files were preserved during processing, with the series arranged in an approximate chronological order.
    - International Community College., 1973-1974.; ca. 50 items. (Box 148, Folder 11-12)
    - Personal Data Page and Applications., 1953. (Box 148, Folder 13)
    - Lecture tours., 1960-1961.; ca. 25 items. (Box 148, Folder 14-15)
    - Lecture tours., 1964-1968.; ca. 200 items. (Box 149, Folder 1-8)
    - Lecture tours., 1969-1973.; ca. 50 items. (Box 150, Folder 1-5)
  - Subseries 7B: San Francisco State College,., 1957-1966; 1 box.
    Material related to Rexroth's lectures and workshops at the San Francisco State College Poetry Center, and four folders of student work.
    - San Francisco State Poetry Center--Printed materials., 1965-1966.; ca. 25 items. (Box 150, Folder 6)
    - San Francisco State Poetry Center--Student work., 1957.; ca. 100 items. (Box 150, Folder 7-8)
    - San Francisco State Poetry Center--Student work., 1957.; ca. 100 items. (Box 151, Folder 1-2)
  - Subseries 7C: UC Santa Barbara,., 1968-1974; 6 boxes.
    Administrative papers, memoranda and teaching files related to Rexroth's appointment in the English department at UCSB. The teaching files primarily include course evaluations and student work from English 183 and 100. The original contents of the files were preserved during processing, with the similar materials arranged in approximate chronological order. See box 120 for an oversize student poetry project from Winter, 1969.
    - Administrative papers., 1968-1972.; ca. 200 items. (Box 151, Folder 3-8)
    - Appointment correspondence., 1967-1973.; ca. 50 items. (Box 151, Folder 9)
      Letters and memos regarding Rexroth's teaching appointments at UCSB.
    - Extension school., 1970-1975.; 5 items. (Box 151, Folder 10)
    - Publications., 1969-1973.; 3 items. (Box 151, Folder 11)
      Brochures on the UCSB Conference on Effective Teaching, University Vacation Center, and a Hustler's Handbook.
    - UCSB teaching files., 1968-1974. (Box 152, Box 153, Box 154, Box 155, Box 156)
      Student evaluations and course work. Arranged chronologically by academic quarter, where possible.